<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Dennis Riis Personal Site</title>
    <link>https://www.driis.dk/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Dennis Riis Personal Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>da-DK</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 17:05:10 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.driis.dk/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is TypeScript and why should I care ? </title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2012/10/what-is-typescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 17:05:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2012/10/what-is-typescript/</guid>
      <description>This tuesday, I watched Anders Hejlsberg present Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s new language bet, TypeScript. This is basically JavaScript with types. It compiles to JavaScript, so, at runtime, it is JavaScript, nothing else. And therefore, it will run whereever JavaScript can run: In any browser, on node.js and so on.
TypeScript adds types as a first class citizen to JavaScript. This means you can use classes and interfaces in your code, and have the compiler do type checking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new home for the Chrome Password Recovery Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2011/04/new-home-for-chrome-password-recovery-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 20:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2011/04/new-home-for-chrome-password-recovery-tool/</guid>
      <description>In 2008, I created the Chrome Password Recovery Tool. However, the download links on that page have been lost in a server migration.
Since I have been getting some email about the absence of a download of the tool, I decided to release it as open source on CodePlex. So go get it from here, if you need it.
This latest version supports the latest Chrome version (10), and enables reading the passwords while Chrome is running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This blog now running MVC3 and RavenDB !</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2011/03/blog-now-running-mvc3-and-ravendb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 18:51:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2011/03/blog-now-running-mvc3-and-ravendb/</guid>
      <description>From today, this blog will be running a home-grown blogging system built on MVC3, Razor and RavenDB.
It had been running Sitecore Express until now, but i decided to ditch it. A Sitecore installation is simply too much of a hassle for a simple site like this. Also, the rich text editor in Sitecore was not really fit for posting code snippets. I will be refining this new blogging solution over the next few weeks, and hopefully it will give me a renewed interest in actually posting content on this blog :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Relative Path Facility For Castle Windsor</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2010/02/a-relative-path-facility-for-castle-windsor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 22:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2010/02/a-relative-path-facility-for-castle-windsor/</guid>
      <description>At work, we use Castle Windsor for Dependency Injection. In Castle Windsor, as with any dependency injection framework, you can configure components identified by an interface, that can be resolved at runtime using the dependency injection framework. Components can have dependencies, which can be yet other components and so on. In this way, you can have your dependency injection framework create a whole graph of objects for you.
One limitation we run into now and then, is with components, that depend on a file path to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Expression Trees To Break The Law Of Demeter</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2010/01/using-expression-trees-to-break-the-law-of-demeter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2010 18:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2010/01/using-expression-trees-to-break-the-law-of-demeter/</guid>
      <description>I am sure most programmers have heard about the Law Of Demeter, which is the principle that a classshould only have limited knowledge about other classes, and only talk to objects closely related to the current object. This is sometimes presented as &#34;you should not have more than one dot in each expression&#34;. In other words, this would be breaking the law: 
string name = order.Customer.Name; While I do appreciate the idea behind the Law Of Demeter, specifically that individual classes should not know too much about each other; I think the above code would often be perfectly acceptable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last day at TechEd</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2009/11/last-day-at-teched/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2009 09:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2009/11/last-day-at-teched/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s friday, and TechEd is over for this time.
My first session on friday was about little-known secrets in Microsoft Silverlight 3. This was a really good session for advanced Silverlight development, and I took away many tricks - including the ability to download and use assemblies dynamically and asynchronously; and to use the OS client stack instead of the browser stack for network access.
Second session was about extending Visual Studio 2010&#39;s architecture modelling tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Four at TechEd over</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2009/11/day-four-at-teched-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2009 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2009/11/day-four-at-teched-over/</guid>
      <description>TechEd is coming to an end, day four is now over. There are three sessions on friday, then it&#39;s over.  I started the day with a session on C# 4.0 Dynamic: The why’s and hows. It was being done by Alex Turner, who is Program Manager for the C# compiler. This was a very interesting walk through why C# should have dynamic features, and why it has been designed as it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third day at TechEd</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2009/11/third-day-at-teched/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 18:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2009/11/third-day-at-teched/</guid>
      <description>Once again, I attended some very interesting talks at TechEd. This mornings sessions was entitled “The daily Scrum”, about doing Scrum and agile development. This was mostly a Q&amp;amp;A session with answers to many of the practical problems one might encounter when trying to be agile.
  Next, I had a real hard time deciding between staying on the agile track and attending the “Tools and Agile Teams” talk versus hearing Don Syme speak about F#.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Two At TechEd Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2009/11/day-two-at-teched-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 22:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2009/11/day-two-at-teched-europe/</guid>
      <description>Today started off fresh with 2 Sharepoint sessions The first one was an introduction to Sharepoint 2010 for developers, and while I haven’t done any development on Sharepoint before, based on the feedback, it will be tons easier to do Sharepoint development with 2010. The second session on Sharepoint was somewhat relevant and somewhat amiss. While it did provide some good information, there was not really anything new, if you had attended the first session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got a Twitter account</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2009/11/got-a-twitter-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 23:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2009/11/got-a-twitter-account/</guid>
      <description>Oh, BTW, I got a twitter account. Follow me on http://twitter.com/dennisriis, if interested. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TechEd Europe 2009 Day One</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2009/11/teched-europe-2009-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 22:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2009/11/teched-europe-2009-day-one/</guid>
      <description>Today was my first day at TechEd Europe 2009 in Berlin, after having arrived to the hotel on sunday evening. I chose to drive to Berlin myself from Denmark, which went just fine, until I scratched a rim on the way down into a very narrow passage to the parking garage. Damn. The TechEd experience so far has been just great, although there was some queue for registration this morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sitecore Dictionary gotcha when using the master database</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2009/06/sitecore-dictionary-gotcha-when-using-the-master-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2009/06/sitecore-dictionary-gotcha-when-using-the-master-database/</guid>
      <description>During some projects at work, we were having a real weird problem with the Sitecore Dictionary feature. This is the built in feature in Sitecore that lets you localize short texts, such as what to put in the &#34;Read more&#34; or &#34;Next page&#34; links on a web page. Of course, there are many ways to do this, but since Dictionary items is a supported Sitecore feature, and they can be edited from within the Sitecore environment, it seems reasonable to use this for Sitecore sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting your public IP from a PowerShell script</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2009/01/getting-your-public-ip-from-a-powershell-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2009 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2009/01/getting-your-public-ip-from-a-powershell-script/</guid>
      <description>I often work on computers at different locations, and often, I need to know what public IP I am using to connect to the internet. Of course, this is easy to find out - I can just go to a website that tells me my IP, such as http://myip.dk/.
But I find this to be suboptimal. If I am configuring something, finding the IP involves firing up a browser, going to the site, and copying the IP displayed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing: The Google Chrome Password Recovery Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2008/12/introducing-the-google-chrome-password-recovery-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2008 17:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2008/12/introducing-the-google-chrome-password-recovery-tool/</guid>
      <description>Today, I wanted to backup all my passwords stored in Google Chrome. I thought that would be an easy task, but it turns out, that this is not supported, at least as far as I can tell. There is an option to view the shared passwords one-by-one, but that was not really an option for me.
So,Â I decided to write a small program to extract the passwords from Chrome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Google Chrome</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2008/10/thoughts-on-google-chrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 09:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2008/10/thoughts-on-google-chrome/</guid>
      <description>I admit it, I am a fan of the new Google Chrome browser. This made me chuckle, however:
Is Google preparing to dominate the world ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making The HTC Touch Diamond Vibrate</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2008/10/making-the-htc-touch-diamond-vibrate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 20:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2008/10/making-the-htc-touch-diamond-vibrate/</guid>
      <description>One of the minor problems I had when making the Stopwatch for my HTC Touch Diamond, was to make the phone vibrate automatically. It seems there are no managed way of doing this. However, after a bit of googling around, I found out that the vibrator typically can be addressed as a LED object using the Open NET CF Framework. So I decided to throw together a tiny wrapper class around this functionality, so I can use it generally in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Stopwatch for Windows Mobile</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2008/10/a-stopwatch-for-windows-mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 20:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2008/10/a-stopwatch-for-windows-mobile/</guid>
      <description>I have got a new mobile phone, a HTC Touch Diamond. Besides the fact that it has a sleek design and is much easier to work with when reading email and browsing the web than my old phone.
However, that it is not the only reason for buying the Diamond. Another, very important reason, is that it runs Windows Mobile 6.1 - and therefore I can write my own programs for it using pretty much the same toolset as I use for any other .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last Day at Jaoo</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2008/09/last-day-at-jaoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2008/09/last-day-at-jaoo/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday was the last official day of the JAOO conference, and once again it featured a bunch of interesting talks. I attended these: 50 in 50
This was todays keynote by Richard P. Gabriel and Guy L. Steele Jr. Before the talk, there had been some speculations about the title; was it 50 programming languages in 50 minutes ? Or what did it mean exactly ? It turned out to be 50 comments about programming and programming languages, in 50 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JAOO Day Two</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2008/09/jaoo-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 10:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2008/09/jaoo-day-two/</guid>
      <description>Today on JAOO has also been packed with interesting talks. I attended these:
 V8: The Javascript engine inside Google Chrome Keynote by Lars Bak about the all-new javascript engine that was implemented by his team in Århus for Google Chrome. This javascript engine is about 10 times faster than other javascript implementations. Lars explained how this is possible in a very dynamic language like javascript, by creating classes that can be reused; if another object with the same properties is created, which tends to happen often.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JAOO Day One</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2008/09/jaoo-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2008 14:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2008/09/jaoo-day-one/</guid>
      <description>Today, I&#39;ve been attending the first day at the JAOO Conference. It has been an interesting day, and I am amazed by all the very talented people that speaks here at the conference, as well as by the quality of the talks. I have been attending these sessions:
 Opening Keynote: Where Are Programming Languages Going, by Anders Hejlsberg In this talk, Anders presented his take on how the programming languages will be evolving in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attending JAOO</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2008/09/attending-jaoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2008 22:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2008/09/attending-jaoo/</guid>
      <description>I will be attending the JAOO conference the next couple of days. It is my first time, but I have high expectations. I am not sure which sessions I will attend, but of course the opening keynote by Anders Hejlsberg will be a must.
I find it hard to choose - there are so many interesting subjects and speakers; and so little time ;-) If you are going to JAOO, feel free to drop a comment with suggestions on which sessions is a must for you, and why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual update on the blog</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2008/09/visual-update-on-the-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2008 12:44:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2008/09/visual-update-on-the-blog/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick post to let you know that the blog has been updated with a much nicer theme. I hope I will get around to adding more interesting content to the blog shortly :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parsing XML with PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2008/06/parsing-xml-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 18:02:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2008/06/parsing-xml-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m addicted to PowerShell. This cool scripting environment is simple to use, and with very few lines of script; it is possible to accomplish tasks that otherwise often would be a lot of tedious work. (If we didn&#39;t have PowerShell, I would propably wip up a C# program to do the same, but PowerShell is really lightweight, is interactive and is generally very forgiving for small tasks where you just &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ReSharper 4 Available</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2008/06/resharper-4-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 19:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2008/06/resharper-4-available/</guid>
      <description>The good folks over at Jetbrains has finally released version 4 of their ReSharper productivity enhancing tool with support for C#3.0.
Highly recommended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clever use of C# 3.0 LINQ Expressions</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2008/06/clever-use-of-csharp-3-linq-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 19:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2008/06/clever-use-of-csharp-3-linq-expressions/</guid>
      <description>Jafar Husain shows us a quite clever way to use a C# 3.0 LINQ expression to get a symbol name. I think this is a really good idea to use in cases when you need the name of a symbol as a string, since it avoids using hard-coded strings and gives us the option to use automatic refactorings without breaking stuff. And since it is implemented as an extension method; it does not pollute the interface of your classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create an ASP .NET Captcha Control (part 2)</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2008/05/how-to-create-an-asp-.net-captcha-control-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2008 19:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2008/05/how-to-create-an-asp-.net-captcha-control-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the second in a&amp;nbsp;3 part series on how to create an ASP .NET Captcha control. The previous post can be found here. This time we will look at how the CAPTCHA image can be generated using the built-in .NET framework classes.
Image generation approach
As described in the first post, the idea is to create an image showing a word, and let the user repeat it by typing it into a textbox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to: Create an ASP.NET CAPTCHA Control (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2008/04/how-to-create-an-asp.net-captcha-control-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2008 17:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2008/04/how-to-create-an-asp.net-captcha-control-part-1/</guid>
      <description>As I explained in my previous post, I developed a CAPTCHA ASP.NET control for this blog. In the next few posts, I will explain the steps involved in doing this, and how you can develop your own CAPTCHA control.
Preparations
There are some variations on CAPTCHA tests, the most common one requiring the user to input the characters displayed on an image. The idea is that only a human will be able to read these characters; so if the challenge response is correct, it is most likely a &amp;quot;real human&amp;quot; submitting the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking ASP.NET: Trace information</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2008/04/hacking-asp.net-trace-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 22:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2008/04/hacking-asp.net-trace-information/</guid>
      <description>All ASP .NET developers propably know about the trace feature in ASP .NET. Provided you have enabled tracing in web.config, (using &amp;lt;trace enabled=&#34;true&#34; /&amp;gt; in the system.web element; requesting the url /trace.axd will provide you with a nice list of trace information for the previous requests.
I have often thought about putting the wealth of information to better use; perhaps making more detailed reports based on the trace information. This could be useful during testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fighting comment spam</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2008/03/fighting-comment-spam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2008 20:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2008/03/fighting-comment-spam/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been hit by comment spam. Suddenly, one of the posts on this site had _a lot_ of comments, all with advertisements for some suspect sites. Needless to say, I&#39;ve removed those comments.
So, what to do about that ? I decided to implement a CAPTCHA on the site. It is a pretty standard one, requiring you to repeat a word, that is shown as an image and garbled, so that image recognition software has a hard time interpreting it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got one of those RSS thingys</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2008/02/got-one-of-those-rss-thingys/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2008 21:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2008/02/got-one-of-those-rss-thingys/</guid>
      <description>Someone pointed out that there was no RSS feed on my blog - i forgot to add it.
It has been fixed now, and you should be able to read my blog in your favourite&amp;nbsp;RSS aggregator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging ASP .NET memory leak - watch for static references</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2008/02/debugging-asp-.net-memory-leak-watch-for-static-references/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 21:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2008/02/debugging-asp-.net-memory-leak-watch-for-static-references/</guid>
      <description>A while ago, I needed to debug an ASP .NET website, which was eating more and more memory the longer it was running, and never seemed to release the memory again. Even though the number of concurrent users was more or less constant, the memory usage seemed to be proportional to the total number of sessions since last application restart.
What was happening here ? Could it be session-state elements that never got garbage collected ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Built on Sitecore Xpress</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2008/02/built-on-sitecore-xpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 21:11:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2008/02/built-on-sitecore-xpress/</guid>
      <description>As from today, this blog runs on Sitecore Xpress. I have spent the day setting it up.
So, what is Sitecore Xpress ? Sitecore Xpress is a personal edition of the professional Sitecore CMS product, which just recently was released and made free of charge for developers. This is really cool, since Sitecore is a very good, mature and professional CMS, that has loads of features and is built on .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sitecore certification</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2007/09/sitecore-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2007 21:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2007/09/sitecore-certification/</guid>
      <description>Sitecore is a .NET CMS system developed in Denmark by Sitecore A/S. We are starting to use the product more and more at work. Today I attended the second Sitecore development course in Copenhagen, &#34;SCD2&#34;. So now I am a certified Sitecore developer ;-) Sitecore is a rather good CMS system (in my humble opinion). Some of the forces is that is easy to extend, and extensions can be created in well known technologies such as .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NEF File reader is on hold ...</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2007/09/nef-file-reader-is-on-hold/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2007 21:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2007/09/nef-file-reader-is-on-hold/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;nbsp;have not had very much time to blog nor work on my NEF file reader project for a while. It has been turbulent and busy times at work, lately. This post is just to let you know, that the project is curently on hold. Perhaps I will resume it later, when I have more free time at hand. If anyone is interested in a peek at the source code as it looks now (incomplete and raw), please let me know; and I can mail it to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NEF file reader update</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2007/08/nef-file-reader-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2007 21:44:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2007/08/nef-file-reader-update/</guid>
      <description>Progress on the NEF / RAW file reader is slow, since i only work on it occasionally when I feel like coding in my spare time. However, I made some progress tonight, that I would like to update you about. First, NEF files are really TIFF files. So I need to parse them as a TIFF file to get some useful information out of them. TIFF files consists of so-called IFD tags, which in parts contains metadata about the image as well as the actual image data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hobby project - Nikon NEF file reader</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2007/07/hobby-project-nikon-nef-file-reader/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2007 21:40:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2007/07/hobby-project-nikon-nef-file-reader/</guid>
      <description>So, my new hobby is digital photography. I have bought a slightly used Nikon D50 camera, and has already taken a lot of pictures. If you&#39;re into digital photography, you will know that most cameras can produce both JPG and RAW output, where the JPG images are compressed by the camera firmware before being written to the flash card. The RAW files are uncompressed data as it was sampled by the camera CMOS (typically).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a HTTP module to enforce a single domain</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2007/07/using-a-http-module-to-enforce-a-single-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2007 21:35:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2007/07/using-a-http-module-to-enforce-a-single-domain/</guid>
      <description>When I first setup this blog, you could access it on both &#34;driis.dk&#34; and &#34;www.driis.dk&#34;. For various reasons, it is best practice to have a single url for the same content (it makes analyzing the site traffic easier, and avoids ambiguous URLs), so I wanted to setup the site to just use the www version of the domain name. Now, there is a couple of ways you could do this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up BlogEngine.NET</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2007/07/setting-up-blogengine.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2007 21:33:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2007/07/setting-up-blogengine.net/</guid>
      <description>After deciding to get this blog, I needed to find some software to run it on. I briefly considered writing it myself, but decided that it would be too much effort, and that I probably never would be able to finish it, considering work and other projects. So I started hunting around for some open source blogging software, and after an hour of googling, I decided on BlogEngine.NET. My main considerations where that it needed to be open source .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got a blog</title>
      <link>https://www.driis.dk/2007/07/got-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2007 21:21:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.driis.dk/2007/07/got-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>So, I decided today that I needed a blog. So here it is, me blogging about programming in general, .NET and my everyday experiences.&amp;nbsp; Why does the world need another blog; you might ask ? Well, it is an experiment for now. I will try to provide some interesting content - and at the same time it will be a place for me to document various findings and thoughts. Anyways, it is much better than the old &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>